Swan mss., 1918-1949 LMC 2005
Lilly Library
Swan mss.
1918-1949
Lilly Library
Swan, William J. (William James), 1896-1978
LMC 2005
2 Boxes 2 standard
The Swan mss., 1918-1949, consist of letters, photographs, and printed materials relating to William Swan's army service in World War I and later family papers and documents.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchase: 2003
Biographical Note
William James Swan, 1896-1978, was born to William E. and Augusta Juniata Swan in Gas City, Indiana. Swan served during World War I as Sgt. 1/CL, QMC in the 38th division. After the war, Swan married Jessie Walton Gallaher and worked at Smokeless Fuel Co. in Charleston, West Virginia.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of letters, documents, and photographs from Swan to his family in Gas City, Indiana. Documents include legal papers, wills, real estate, etc. Also included are 67 photographs of both army scenes and his family and two small notebooks. 47 letters to his family, mostly from France and Belgium, and 6 letters by others, as well as a group of printed and manuscript ephemera, complete the collection.
See Vertical File for itemized inventory of correspondence.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged following original order.
World War, 1914-1918; Indiana--History
- World War, 1914-1918, 1914-1922 (Box Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1918-1919 (Box Box 1)
    - 1918, January 1 - 1918, December 31 (Box Box 1)
    - 1919, January 1 - 1919, April 30 (Box Box 1)
    - 1919, May 1 - 1919, December 31 (Box Box 1)
  - Diary 1917-1922 (Box Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous, 1914-1918 (Box Box 1)
  - News Clippings (Box Box 1)
  - Photographs (Box Box 1)
- Photographs (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - Groups (Box 2)
  - Men (Box 2)
  - Women (Box 2)
- News Clippings (Box 2)
- Travels (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous (Box 2)
- Deeds, 1887-1956 (Box 2)
- Correspondence, 1900-1956 (Box 2)
  - 1949, January 1 - 1956, December 1, 1949-1956 (Box 2)
  - 1948, August 1 - 1948, December 31 (Box 2)
  - 1947, January 1 - 1948, July 31, 1947-1948 (Box 2)
  - 1900 - 1946, December 1 (Box 2)
- Address Book (Box 2)